# Karl Roush

karlroush.com • (706) 873-1987 • US Citizen karl.roush@gmail.com



## Overview

BS/MS Aerospace Engineering graduating with Highest Honors in 3 years; research experience with jet engines, drones, & hands-on shop fabrication. Current work in hypersonics, smart airports, space based ISR, & aircraft emissions. Interests + learning in MBSE, QE, ML/AI, and information security.

#### Education

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology, MS Aerospace Engineering

BS/MS AE Honors program GPA: 4.00, Propulsion focus

Aug 2017 – May 2020

Georgia Institute of Technology, BS Aerospace Engineering

Summer 2018 Oxford Program, ΣΓΤ Honor society Graduated with Highest Honors (GPA= 3.80)

## **Experience**

**Graduate Research Assistant** 

May 2020 - Present

Aerospace Systems Design Lab

- -Current work on space based ISR, reusable hypersonic vehicles, smart airports, aircraft emissions global policy
- -Fabrication Lead (Aug 2018-20) under AFRL's Aerospace Propulsion Outreach small gas turbine engine design problems

#### **UTSR Gas Turbine Industrial Fellowship**

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Southwest Research Institute: Department of Energy, Office of Fossil Energy

- -Determined viability of hybrid cycle UAVs for surveillance missions & created an NPSS tool for subsequent mission analysis
- -Designed and built laser PIV system for <10% of quoted industry cost for low speed turbulence testing
- -Standardized NPSS unit conversions for international use, streamlined data collection of drag testing (65% time reduction)

### **Competitive Innovation Consultant**

May 2017 - Present

MindSumo: A competitive problem-solving platform; Awarded wins from AAA, Mozilla, NASA, Siemens, GSK, et. al

-Ranked in the top 5 of 350,000+ solvers, Chosen as a winner for 93% of competitions (Mindsumo All-Star average= 20%)

## **Projects**

## Jet Engine Cycle Analysis & Optimization

Jan. 2020- May 2020

Off-design cycle design & analysis of a separate flow turbofan in NPSS; Optimized engine for range in a scaled Boeing 737 800

#### **Natural Language Processing Semantris Solver**

July 2020

Built a solver for the Google experiment Semantris using Computer Vision + NLP model built from Google News data

## Notable Awards/Certificates

#### Wells Fargo Campus Analytics Challenge Winner (Two Times)

Dec 2018, 2019

Machine learning analytics challenge, 2018= model for minimizing carbon footprint, 2019= Topic generation based on NASA datasets

### Eagle Scout Rank Award, Bronze Palm and Gold Palm

Mar 2015

Awarded Bronze Palm in October 2015, Gold Palm September 2016

## International Best Use of Data- NASA Space Apps Hackathon

Sept 2016

First Place Overall (Project: EvaS)- Space Apps Next Gen NYC Hackathon Challenge

Developed a search for Extra-Vehicular Activities via NASA's public data in HTML/CSS and JavaScript over the course of ~14 hours

#### Skills and Certifications

 $\textbf{Programs:} \ \mathsf{NPSS}, \ \mathsf{SolidWorks}, \ \mathsf{MATLAB}, \ \mathsf{Git}$ 

Languages: Python, C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Design: Photoshop, Premiere, Cura

Machine shop certified

Mill, lathe, band saw, water jet, sanders

Class 4 Laser Safety Certified Laser and Lab Safety Training

German, Latin
ILR Level 2 fluency

## **Clubs and Activities**

American Institute of Aeronautics & Astronautics Graduate Liaison, GT Student Chapter (Chair 2019-20) **GreyHat, Information Security** 

**GT Hytech Racing (FSAE)** 

Vice President (2019-20)

Aero/Composites sub-team

## **Relevant Coursework**

Propulsion System Design

Adv. Aircraft Propulsion Optimization Algorithms

Aircraft Design

Flight Dynamics & Controls

## **Personal Interests**

3D printing Metal work & painting

Information security

Machine learning

Service via Eagles@GT